Ippei Shoji

Tokyo, Tokyo, Japan



linkedin.com/in/ippei-shoji-2663a0140



arpena1pay@gmail.com

Summary

Web Application Developer experienced for around 5 years, including 2.5y developer internship. mainly developing informational systems with Ruby/RoR/MySQL. additionally some SRE-like experiences; incident managements for enterprise systems, DevOps with AWS/GCP, Docker, and several CI/CD services. recently manipulated by ML/DS things while planning and developing corporate data infrastructures, which certainly could accelerate company's business in near future.

although I was studying law, got crazy about software engineering, which began from HTML/CSS/JS implementation for emarketing, that I chose the path now on

< Expertise >

Ruby / Javascript / Nodejs / Python / SQL / RoR / Sinatra / ExpressJS / WordPress / MySQL / SQLite3 / Apache2 / Nginx / Docker / Docker Compose / Git / CircleCI / AWS / GCP

Experience



Web Application Developer

CUEBiC,ink

Oct 2018 - Present (1 year 8 months +)

■ built in-house data utilization along company's strategy

from proposal to direction as project manager, system design as architect, implementation as product owner, scripting as developer. currently working in two main projects for building in-house web applications. # from static/dynamic modeling, developed some information systems to visualize and analyze in-house data with a simple data-storing pipeline with AWS (EC2/ECS, Batch, RDS, etc..), Docker, Google/Yahoo Ads APIs # on the way of data storage things, optimized a biz process by -99% (150min/d -> 10min/w) via automating byhand procedures with RoR, Fluentd, some AWS services

address problems about in-house data storing via simple table-data ML trials using sklearn/LightGBM with Python3

■ brought more work efficiency to my team with building sort of service desk

problem: IT related questions from biz teams towards each member personally. neither ticket tracking nor knowledge management

solution: integrated all the interface to Slack. architected and developed all that slack API triggers JIRA API Ticket creation on AWS Lambda. this enabled to log and visualize working time, which brings even another upcoming efficiency into not only ourselves, but communication with biz teams.

■ SRE-like work for enterprise systems

have been doing service maintenance/enhancement when affiliate web site systems (LAMP) get in trouble # doing: address the problem with AWS CloudWatch or other logging/monitoring services, then solve it and turn back the service to available state ASAP.

transferred workflows had been differently managed by each case to ITIL based incident management. formatted RCA docs and JIRA use.

Web Application Developer

CUEBiC,ink

Jul 2015 - Sep 2018 (3 years 3 months)

development for internal information systems

experienced team development with Git, Github on Git-flow

designed and implemented several RoR apps with Rspec testing

installed new workflows along the updated app to several biz teams

■ DevOps into one build process with CircleCI

addressed cause of the time-consuming problem, then researched and tested each solution # by upgrading version from 1.* to 2.0 and installing new cache function, shortened building duration by 89% (about 45min to 5min)

■ BPO about landing page optimization process with requirement definition

actually planned to build new system but it was too much. Biz team needed 1st step so that I pivoted the plan to workflow rebuilding

defined requirement details from biz team, and reframed the LPO workflow # optimized the process duration from 10+ days to ave 3.5 days on average.

Marketing Assistant

SkyBall

Nov 2016 - Oct 2017 (1 year)

helped run business from recording movies to social network marketing as intern.



V-KAIWA

Mar 2017 - Jul 2017 (5 months)

supported them as internship and as one user (those who have grown up in a country where the English education doesn't work well so much) by 3D modeling with Maya Autodesk and Unity, Photoshopping

Marketing And Advertising

CUEBiC,ink

Mar 2014 - Jun 2015 (1 year 4 months)

run online advertising campaigns or landing page optimisation.

Education



Hitotsubashi University

Bachelor's degree, Law 2014 - 2018



Bachelor's degree, Law

2017 - 2017

Licenses & Certifications



Associate Cloud Engineer - Google Cloud Platform Certified

Issued Dec 2019 - Expires Dec 2021 te4YPG